<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>技术博客</title>
  <link href="https://yourblog.github.io"/>
  <link href="https://yourblog.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2025-07-22T13:19:05.000Z</updated>
  <id>https://yourblog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <generator>Node.js RSS Generator</generator>

  <entry>
    <title>Building Developer Tools for Context Engineering: What Manus Taught Us and What We&#x27;re Building</title>
    <link href="https://yourblog.github.io/2025/07/22/building-developer-tools-for-context-engineering-what-manus-taught-us-and-what-we/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-22T13:19:05.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://yourblog.github.io/2025/07/22/building-developer-tools-for-context-engineering-what-manus-taught-us-and-what-we/</id>
    <content type="html">
When the Manus team playfully described their AI development journey as &quot;Stochastic Graduate Descent,&quot; it was more than just a clever pun on the familiar &quot;Stochastic Gradient Descent&quot; (SGD). They weren&#x27;t just being self-deprecating, they were highlighting a fundamental problem in the industry: proper tools for context engineering simply don&#x27;t exist yet.
Their recent blog post offers a rare look into production-level context engineering. But between the lines, it reveals something equally important – the enormous friction developers face when building context-aware AI systems. Every insight they shared, from KV-cache optimization to attention manipulation, represents hours of manual debugging, trial and error, and custom tooling.

This got us thinking: what if context engineering had proper developer tools? What would they look like, and how would they change the way we build AI agents?

The Current State: Flying Blind

Today&#x27;s context engineering workflow resembles web development from the 1990s – lots of manual work, limited visibility, and debugging through print statements. Consider what Manus had to discover the hard way:

Performance Debugging Without Metrics
Manus identified KV-cache hit rate as their most critical metric, but most developers have no visibility into cache performance. They&#x27;re optimizing blind, discovering 10x cost differences only after running production workloads.

Tool Management Through Trial and Error
The &quot;tool explosion&quot; problem that Manus describes, where adding more tools makes agents less effective, is something every team discovers independently. There&#x27;s no systematic way to analyze tool usage patterns or optimize action spaces.

Context Architecture Through Intuition
Manus&#x27;s insight about using file systems as external memory, or their attention manipulation through todo.md files, emerged from extensive experimentation. These patterns could be discoverable through proper tooling.

Error Analysis Via Log Diving
Their counterintuitive principle of &quot;keeping the wrong stuff in&quot; for error recovery becomes obvious when you have tools to analyze failure patterns and recovery success rates.

What Manus&#x27;s Experience Teaches Us About Tool Requirements

Reading their lessons carefully, we can extract specific requirements for context engineering tools:

1. Performance Visibility Tools
The Problem: Developers can&#x27;t see KV-cache performance, token costs, or context efficiency.

What&#x27;s Needed:
Real-time cache hit rate monitoring
Token cost breakdown by context segment
Context reuse pattern analysis
Performance impact visualization of context changes
2. Tool Management Interfaces
The Problem: No systematic way to manage large tool ecosystems or understand tool selection patterns.

What&#x27;s Needed:
Tool usage analytics and optimization suggestions
Visual action space design and testing
Dynamic tool masking configuration interfaces
Tool conflict detection and resolution
3. Context Architecture Designers
The Problem: Context structure design happens through trial and error.

What&#x27;s Needed:
Visual context flow designers
Compression strategy testing environments
Memory system simulation and optimization
Context pattern libraries and templates
4. Debugging and Observability Platforms
The Problem: Agent behavior is opaque and difficult to debug.

What&#x27;s Needed:
Step-by-step agent execution visualization
Attention heatmaps and focus tracking
Error pattern analysis and recovery optimization
A/B testing frameworks for context variations
Enter Context Space: A Tool-First Response

At Context Space, we&#x27;ve been building with these exact challenges in mind. Our tool-first philosophy isn&#x27;t just about making integrations easier. It&#x27;s about creating the developer experience that context engineering desperately needs.

Standardized, Observable Tools

Where Manus had to manually implement tool masking and state management, Context Space provides standardized tool interfaces that include:

Built-in usage analytics and performance monitoring
Automatic tool conflict detection
Standardized error handling and recovery patterns
Tool recommendation based on context and task patterns
Dynamic Context Composition

Manus&#x27;s file-system-as-memory approach inspired our dynamic context building capabilities:

Visual context flow designers that let you see how information flows
Automatic compression with recoverable strategies
Memory system templates for different use cases
Context efficiency optimization suggestions
Developer Experience First

While Manus had to build their insights through &quot;four complete framework rebuilds,&quot; Context Space aims to make these patterns discoverable:

IDE Integration: Debug context flows directly in your development environment
Real-time Monitoring: See KV-cache performance, tool usage, and context efficiency live
Pattern Libraries: Reusable context engineering patterns based on proven approaches
A/B Testing: Compare context strategies with real metrics
The Tool Discovery Problem

One of Context Space&#x27;s core innovations addresses something Manus hinted at: as tool ecosystems grow, discovery becomes critical. Our tool discovery and recommendation engine uses:

Context-aware tool suggestions based on current task patterns
Usage analytics to surface the most effective tool combinations
Automatic tool conflict resolution
Progressive disclosure to manage complexity
What This Looks Like in Practice

Imagine rebuilding Manus&#x27;s agent with proper tooling:

Performance Optimization Made Visible
Instead of discovering cache performance issues in production, developers see real-time KV-cache metrics with suggestions for improvement. Context changes show immediate performance impact.

Tool Management Made Systematic
Rather than manually implementing tool masking, developers use visual interfaces to design action spaces, with automatic conflict detection and usage analytics guiding optimization.

Context Architecture Made Discoverable
Instead of reinventing memory patterns, developers choose from proven templates (file-system memory, attention manipulation, error preservation) with clear documentation and usage examples.

Debugging Made Transparent
Rather than guessing why an agent made a particular decision, developers see step-by-step execution flows, attention patterns, and decision trees with clear causality chains.

The Infrastructure Layer We&#x27;re Missing

Manus&#x27;s experience reveals that context engineering needs what web development got in the 2000s: a mature infrastructure layer that handles the common patterns so developers can focus on their unique challenges.

Context Space is building this layer:

Unified Tool Interface: One API for all external tools and services
Context Management Engine: Handles optimization, compression, and memory management
Observability Platform: Real-time insights into agent behavior and performance
Developer Toolchain: IDE integrations, debugging interfaces, and testing frameworks
The Future of Context Engineering Tools

Looking ahead, we see context engineering tools evolving in several directions:

Visual Context Design
Moving from text-based configuration to visual flow designers where developers can see and manipulate context structures directly.

Intelligent Optimization
AI-powered suggestions for context optimization, tool selection, and performance improvements based on usage patterns.

Collaborative Development
Tools that enable teams to share context patterns, collaborate on agent designs, and build on each other&#x27;s discoveries.

Production Monitoring
Comprehensive observability for production AI agents, with automatic anomaly detection and optimization suggestions.

Building the Context Engineering Platform

The lessons from Manus are clear: context engineering is too important to leave to trial and error. The field needs professional-grade tools that make best practices discoverable and optimization systematic.

This is exactly what we&#x27;re building at Context Space. Our tool-first infrastructure isn&#x27;t just about making integrations easier, it&#x27;s more about creating the development experience that teams like Manus needed but had to build themselves.

Every principle they discovered through their self-termed &quot;Stochastic Graduate Descent&quot; becomes a feature in our platform:
KV-cache optimization → real-time performance monitoring
Tool explosion management → intelligent tool discovery and management
Memory architecture → dynamic context building capabilities
Error recovery → systematic debugging and observability
The Developer Experience We Deserve

Context engineering is becoming the foundation of all serious AI development. But it shouldn&#x27;t require multiple framework rebuilds and years of trial and error to get right.

The future belongs to teams that can iterate quickly on context strategies, optimize performance systematically, and debug agent behavior transparently. This requires tools that make context engineering principles discoverable, optimization automatic, and debugging straightforward.

We&#x27;re building that future at Context Space. Every challenge that Manus solved through manual experimentation, we&#x27;re turning into a tool that makes the next team faster.

There&#x27;s no question that Context Engineering is quickly becoming essential. The real question is whether we want to continually reinvent the wheel ourselves over and over again, or use proper tools designed for the job.

Ready to experience context engineering with proper tooling?

?? Try Context Space and see what context engineering looks like with the right tools

?? Explore our GitHub to understand our tool-first approach

The &quot;Stochastic Gradient Descent&quot; era of context engineering is ending. The systematic, tool-supported era is beginning.
</content>
    <summary>When the Manus team playfully described their AI development journey as Stochast...</summary>
    <category term="技术"/>
    <category term="AI"/>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Context Engineering for AI Agents: Key Lessons from Manus</title>
    <link href="https://yourblog.github.io/2025/07/22/context-engineering-for-ai-agents-key-lessons-from-manus/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-22T13:19:05.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://yourblog.github.io/2025/07/22/context-engineering-for-ai-agents-key-lessons-from-manus/</id>
    <content type="html">
Context engineering is quickly emerging as one of the most critical disciplines in AI development, yet it remains a field still in its experimental phase. Best practices are not yet codified, so a transparent look into a production system is invaluable.
The team at Manus AI recently published a post on their experiences building a real-world agent, offering significant insights gained from four complete framework rebuilds. These lessons provide a practical roadmap for anyone building production-level AI systems.
The Primary Metric: KV-Cache Hit Rate
While task success is a common goal, the Manus team emphasizes that the single most important metric for a production agent is its KV-cache hit rate. This is more than a simple performance optimization; it is a core architectural constraint that directly impacts economic viability.
In agentic systems, the input context grows substantially with each turn, while the output (the next action) remains short. Manus reports an average input-to-output token ratio of 100:1. This makes prefix caching essential. With cached tokens costing 10 times less than uncached ones ($0.30/MTok vs. $3.00/MTok), efficient caching is fundamental to a sustainable product.
This focus leads to three guiding principles for context design:

Stable Prefixes: Even a single token difference can invalidate the entire cache downstream. Avoid dynamic elements like timestamps in system prompts.
Append-Only Context: Never modify previous actions or observations. Ensure deterministic serialization (even JSON key ordering matters).
Explicit Cache Breakpoints: When manual cache management is required, carefully place breakpoints to account for cache expiration patterns.
This represents a shift in thinking: context engineering isn&#x27;t just about what information to include, but how to structure it for maximum reusability.

The &quot;Tool Explosion&quot; Problem
As an agent&#x27;s capabilities expand, so does its collection of tools. However, a larger toolkit can paradoxically make the agent less effective. Manus identifies this as the &quot;tool explosion&quot; problem, where an expanded action space leads the model to select suboptimal or inefficient paths.
Their solution is both elegant and effective: mask tool availability instead of removing tools from the context. By keeping tool definitions stable and using logit masking, they preserve cache coherence and gain fine-grained control over the agent&#x27;s action space.
Memory Architecture: The File System as External Context
Even with large context windows, their limits become apparent in complex tasks. The Manus team’s solution is to treat the file system as the ultimate context: unlimited, persistent, and directly accessible by the agent. This allows for &quot;recoverable compression,&quot; where information like a webpage&#x27;s content can be offloaded from the prompt as long as a URL or file path allows the agent to restore it when needed.
Attention Management Through Recitation
One of the most novel insights from Manus involves manipulating the model&#x27;s attention through recitation. Their agents create and continuously update a todo.md file. The purpose is not just organization; it is a deliberate technique to guide the model. By reciting objectives at the end of the context, the agent pushes the global plan into the model&#x27;s most recent attention span, reducing goal drift on long tasks.
Error Handling as a Feature
A counterintuitive but powerful lesson is to keep error information in the context. Failed actions and stack traces provide crucial learning signals that help the model self-correct. Manus argues that error recovery is a clear indicator of advanced agentic behavior, a factor often overlooked in academic benchmarks.
Breaking Patterns: The Few-Shot Trap
While useful in many applications, extensive few-shot prompting can create harmful patterns in agentic systems. A model can fall into a &quot;rhythm,&quot; repeating an action because it matches the context&#x27;s pattern, not because it is optimal. The solution is structured variation: introducing controlled randomness in formatting and phrasing to break these emergent patterns.
The Meta-Lesson: An Experimental Science
Beyond any specific technique, the Manus experience shows that context engineering is fundamentally an experimental science. Their process involved rebuilding their framework four times, with each iteration yielding new insights. This underscores the current reality of the field: progress comes from methodical testing and refinement.
Implications for the Industry
Several broader lessons emerge from this work:
Performance First: Production engineering must prioritize cache efficiency and cost from day one.
Stability Over Flexibility: Consistent, predictable structures often outperform dynamic systems that break caching.
Design for Messiness: Real-world agent behavior includes errors and suboptimal paths, and the system must be designed for this reality.
Externalize Memory: Context windows, regardless of size, should be supplemented with external memory systems like the file system.
Structure is Attention: How information is structured is as important as what information is included.
Looking Forward
The experiences from Manus point toward context engineering evolving from an art into a more formal science. Their systematic approach provides a roadmap for the industry. Key areas for future development will include standardized metrics beyond task success, better architectures for managing large toolsets, and more sophisticated external memory systems.
The transition from AI demos to production-grade agents requires this kind of systematic thinking. The willingness of teams like Manus to share their insights accelerates the entire field&#x27;s learning curve, offering a starting point to avoid common pitfalls. The future of AI agents will be built by those who understand these production realities. Context engineering may be experimental, but it is no longer optional.

Further Reading:
Original Manus blog post with detailed technical implementation
The field is young, the challenges are real, and the opportunities are enormous. The question isn&#x27;t whether context engineering will become critical—it&#x27;s whether you&#x27;ll learn these lessons through experimentation or through others&#x27; experience.
</content>
    <summary>Context engineering is quickly emerging as one of the most critical disciplines ...</summary>
    <category term="技术"/>
    <category term="AI"/>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Two Approaches to Context Engineering: Manus vs. Context Space</title>
    <link href="https://yourblog.github.io/2025/07/22/two-approaches-to-context-engineering-manus-vs/"/>
    <updated>2025-07-22T13:19:05.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://yourblog.github.io/2025/07/22/two-approaches-to-context-engineering-manus-vs/</id>
    <content type="html">
Context engineering is quickly becoming a cornerstone of modern AI development, driving new approaches across the industry. Recently, the team at Manus AI shared their hard-earned lessons from building production-grade AI agents, offering valuable insights into the practical challenges of context management.

Reading their post felt like looking in a mirror, and yet seeing a completely different reflection. Both Manus and Context Space are deeply invested in solving the context engineering puzzle, but we&#x27;re approaching it from fundamentally different angles. This presents a fascinating case study in how the same core problem can spawn complementary solutions.

Manus: Runtime Optimization Masters

Manus has taken a performance-first approach to context engineering, focusing on how to make the most efficient use of context within existing LLM architectures. Their six core principles reveal a team that has wrestled with the practical realities of production AI systems:

The Manus Philosophy
KV-Cache Optimization: Treating cache hit rates as the most critical metric for production agents
Tool Masking: Using logits manipulation to control tool availability without breaking cache coherence
File System as Context: Leveraging persistent storage as unlimited, externalized memory
Attention Manipulation: Using techniques like todo.md recitation to guide model focus
Error Preservation: Keeping failure traces in context to enable learning
Diversity Injection: Adding controlled variation to prevent pattern lock-in
This approach is deeply technical, performance-conscious, and laser-focused on extracting maximum value from current LLM capabilities.

Context Space: Infrastructure-First Foundation

Context Space, by contrast, has taken an infrastructure-first approach, focusing on making context engineering accessible, secure, and scalable for the broader developer community. Our core philosophy centers around:

The Context Space Philosophy
Tool-First Architecture: Encapsulating all capabilities, including memory and orchestration, as standardized, observable tools
Unified API Layer: Providing a single, consistent interface that abstracts away service-specific complexities
Enterprise Security: Implementing Vault-secured credential management and just-in-time token access
Developer Experience: Building seamless integrations with IDEs and development workflows
Ecosystem Building: Creating a platform where tools can be discovered, shared, and composed
Where Manus optimizes the runtime, Context Space builds the foundation.

The Common Ground: Shared Insights

Despite our different approaches, the convergence of insights is striking:

1. Context is King
Both teams recognize that the future of AI isn&#x27;t just about better models, it&#x27;s about better context management. As Manus puts it: &quot;How you shape the context ultimately defines how your agent behaves.&quot;

2. Production Reality Bites
Neither team is building academic demos. We&#x27;re both grappling with real-world constraints: cost optimization, latency requirements, error handling, and scale challenges that only emerge in production environments.

3. Tool Explosion is Real
Both systems face the challenge of managing growing tool ecosystems. Whether it&#x27;s Manus&#x27;s hundreds of &quot;mysterious tools&quot; or Context Space&#x27;s expanding integration catalog, tool management is a shared pain point.

4. Memory Matters
Both approaches recognize that context windows, no matter how large, aren&#x27;t enough. Manus uses the file system as externalized memory, while Context Space encapsulates memory as a standardized tool.

The Fundamental Divide: Runtime vs Infrastructure
The key difference lies in where we intervene in the AI stack:
Manus: The Performance Specialists
Manus dives deep into LLM internals, things like KV-cache mechanics, attention patterns, and logits manipulation. They&#x27;re asking: &quot;How can we make this agent run faster, cheaper, and more reliably?&quot;

Context Space: The Platform Builders
Context Space focuses on developer experience and ecosystem growth. We&#x27;re asking: &quot;How can we make it easier for thousands of developers to build sophisticated agents without reinventing the wheel?&quot;

The Beautiful Complementarity
What&#x27;s fascinating is how these approaches complement rather than compete:

Manus optimizes the &quot;how&quot;
Their insights about KV-cache optimization, attention manipulation, and error handling are invaluable for any production agent system. These are the kinds of performance patterns that should be baked into every agent runtime.

Context Space standardizes the &quot;what&quot;
Our focus on tool standardization, unified APIs, and developer infrastructure creates the foundation that makes Manus-style optimizations possible at scale.

A Shared Vision for the Future

Both approaches point toward the same inevitable future: sophisticated, context-aware AI agents operating at production scale. But they represent different layers of the same stack:

Infrastructure Layer (Context Space): Standardized tools, secure integrations, developer experience
Runtime Layer (Manus): Performance optimization, attention management, execution efficiency
Application Layer: The actual AI agents that users interact with
The agents of tomorrow will need both: the solid foundation that Context Space provides and the runtime optimizations that Manus masters.

What This Means for the Industry

The parallel evolution of these approaches suggests that context engineering is maturing as a discipline. We&#x27;re moving beyond simple prompt engineering toward a more sophisticated understanding of how to architect AI systems for real-world deployment.

The fact that two teams, working independently, have arrived at such complementary insights validates the importance of this work. Context engineering isn&#x27;t a niche concern, it&#x27;s becoming the foundation of all serious AI development.

Building the Future Together

As we&#x27;ve learned from studying Manus&#x27;s approach, there&#x27;s tremendous value in cross-pollination between different context engineering philosophies. Some of their runtime optimization patterns could inform how we design Context Space&#x27;s SDK. Similarly, our tool standardization approach might inspire new ways to think about agent architecture.

The future of AI agents will be built by teams that understand both the infrastructure challenges and the runtime optimizations. Whether you&#x27;re building the next Manus or integrating with Context Space, we&#x27;re all part of the same mission: making AI agents reliable, efficient, and genuinely useful.

The context engineering revolution is just beginning. Let&#x27;s build it together.

Ready to explore context engineering for yourself?

?? Check out Context Space on GitHub and see how we&#x27;re building the infrastructure layer

?? Read Manus&#x27;s insights to understand the runtime optimization layer

The future needs both approaches. Which layer will you build?
</content>
    <summary>Context engineering is quickly becoming a cornerstone of modern AI development, ...</summary>
    <category term="技术"/>
    <category term="AI"/>
  </entry>
</feed>